myhosting.com 2014-12-20

# Privacy Policy | myhosting.com

April 15, 2014 - (version 1.10) 

**Purpose**

This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) governs all aspects of how myhosting.com (“We”, “Us” and “Our”) collects, uses, maintains and discloses Personal Information from users (“Users”, “You” and “Your”) of this website, http://www.myhosting.com (“Site”) and all Services (“Services”) offered by myhosting.com. myhosting.com is a registered trademark and brand owned and operated by SoftCom Inc. – an Ontario corporation.

**myhosting.com values the privacy of their customers.**

The privacy of Users continues to be very important to myhosting.com since being founded in 1997. myhosting.com complies with the requirements of the Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”).

SoftCom Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your Personal Information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software, mobile applications or behind the login of the Site. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Site, www.myhosting.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [legal@softcom.com](mailto:legal@softcom.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

All content contained on the myhosting.com website is intended only for people 18 years of age and over and myhosting.com does not knowingly collect or use Personal Information from anyone under the age of 18.

**Information that myhosting.com collects.**

myhosting.com, from time-to-time, may collect personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) from Users. This includes name, address, email address and credit card information that you provide, and any correspondence that you have with myhosting.com that occurs by way of telephone, email, online chat, web-based email forms and/or support tickets that are generated for the purpose of communicating and/or resolving any issues related to the Services. myhosting.com also collects additional usage information (“Additional Usage Information”) that is collected electronically about how Users use our Site (e.g. by tracking the number of unique page views received by the pages of the Site, or the domains from which Users originate) or via cookies that can be used to identify the User should they visit the Site again.

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. 

We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. [Click here for more information](http://support.google.com/accounts/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=32050). 

We may set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Session cookies are used to store the contents of your shopping cart, should you choose to complete the check-out process later during your visit to myhosting.com.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as our shopping cart or “save password” features may be limited.

**Third Party Cookies**

The use of cookies by our service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our service providers use persistent cookies for advertising and retargeting purposes. We may tie the information gathered to our Customers’ or Users’ personally identifiable information. For further information on third party cookies, please review their respective privacy policies.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**

Our third party affiliate partners employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs). Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information, but share only information such Order ID, total value of the shopping cart, and the website from which you linked to our Sites. 

To learn more about our affiliate company’s use of clear gifs, please visit the [Commission Junction Privacy Policy](http://www.cj.com/privacy_member.html) or the [ShareASale Privacy Policy](http://www.shareasale.com/agreement.cfm). 

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see the section Access and Consent. 

**Behavioral Targeting/Re-Targeting**

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect both personally and non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Analytics/Log Files**

Additional Usage Information collected may include other information about your visits to our Site. For example, we may collect anonymous information about your computer, such as your IP address (a number assigned to your computer whenever you surf the World Wide Web); the type of Internet browser you are using; the type of computer operating system you are using; or the domain name of the website from which you linked to our Sites. This Additional Usage Information will not be linked to your Personal Information and will only be collected in the aggregate in connection with all the users of our Site for planning, forecasting and/or evaluation purposes. As such, please note that this Policy does not cover aggregated data from which the identity of an individual cannot be determined. myhosting.com retains the right to use anonymous aggregated data in any way that it determines appropriate.

Our Site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your Personal Information from our blog or community forum, contact us using the information at the bottom of this page. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Information about 3 rd party services and/or software**

myhosting.com offers a variety of 3rd party services and/or software that can be used by Users either as an add-on to the Services and/or a download, with your permission, to Your computer to enhance Your experience with the Services, i.e. the Microsoft® Outlook client. Any such add-on(s) and/or downloaded software(s) obtained by way of myhosting.com are subject to separate Privacy Policies from each of their respective 3rd party providers. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any such add-on(s) and/or downloaded software. It is Your responsibility to review and agree to the Privacy Policy of each add-on and/or downloaded software program obtained by way of myhosting.com before using said add-on and/or software. You acknowledge and agree that Your continued use of any such add-on and/or downloaded software constitutes Your consent to the Privacy Policy of said 3rd party. 

We may provide your Personal Information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as offering customer service or payment processing. These companies are authorized to use your Personal Information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Our Site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Our Site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of myhosting.com. If you submit Personal Information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

**Your Consent**

Your provision of Personal Information to myhosting.com means that you agree and consent that myhosting.com may collect, use and disclose your Personal Information in accordance with this Policy. If you do not agree with these terms, you are requested not to provide any Personal Information to myhosting.com. myhosting.com services can only be offered if you provide Personal Information to myhosting.com. Consequently, if you choose not to provide us with any required Personal Information, myhosting.com will not be able to offer you certain services. 

If you do not wish to receive information regarding the products and services offered by myhosting.com and its trusted affiliates, independent contractors and business partners please: (i) send an e-mail to the address listed at the end of this policy; or (ii) log into web—based Control Panel and change the appropriate preferences so as to not receive any correspondence from myhosting.com for any products and services offered by myhosting.com, its trusted affiliates, independent contractors and business partners.

**How myhosting.com uses Personal Information**

myhosting.com may, from time-to-time, use Personal Information collected to: (i) provide Users with a product or service that has been requested; (ii) contact Users directly regarding products and services offered by myhosting.com and its trusted affiliates, independent contractors and business partners; (iii) understand User preferences in order to enhance Users' experience with myhosting.com and such affiliates, independent contractors and business partners; (iv) research the effectiveness of the Site and the marketing, advertising and sales efforts of myhosting.com, its trusted affiliates, independent contractors and business partners; and (v) for the collection of account receivables owed by Users to myhosting.com. myhosting.com does work closely with the Google Advertising Network to present myhosting.com advertisements throughout the Google Advertising Network to myhosting.com customers. Users may opt out of this program at any time by visiting - <http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/> and selecting ‘Opt Out’. 

myhosting.com’s use of Personal Information is limited to these purposes. Unless permitted by law, no Personal Information about a User is collected, without first obtaining the consent of the individual to the collection, use and dissemination of that information.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

myhosting.com will **_never_** disclose your Personal Information without consent except pursuant to the requirements of Section 7(3) – Disclosure without knowledge or consent – of PIPEDA and Division 1 – Protection of Personal Information – of PIPEDA, in which circumstances myhosting.com may be obligated to disclose information without consent.

We may disclose your personal information 

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request,
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so. 
  * if myhosting.com is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of your Personal Information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Personal Information,

The only exception is the information disclosed for the purpose of registering a domain name. Only contract information for a domain name will be provided to the registrar partner(s) in order to complete the registration process. Where obligated or permitted to disclose information without consent, myhosting.com will not disclose more information than is required or requested.

**Maintenance, Retention and Security of Personal Information**

myhosting.com retains Personal Information about Users as long as myhosting.com believes it is necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected. Currently, myhosting.com holds the Personal Information in the City of Toronto, Ontario, Canada.

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

Personal Information about Users that is maintained on our systems is protected using industry standard security measures and myhosting.com complies with the security safeguards principal of Schedule 1, Clause 4.7 of PIPEDA. However, we cannot guarantee that the information submitted to, maintained on, or transmitted from our systems will be completely secure and transmission of information over the Internet is susceptible to possible loss, misrouting, interception and misuse.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Access to Personal Information**

myhosting.com provides individuals with access to Personal Information held about them and complies with the individual access principal of Schedule 1, Clause 4.9 of PIPEDA.

Pursuant to Schedule 1, Clause 4.9.5 of PIPEDA, You may also request that myhosting.com delete Your Personal Information from myhosting.com’s system and records. However, due to technical constraints and the fact that myhosting.com backs up its systems, Personal Information may continue to reside in myhosting.com’s systems after deletion for some time. Individuals, therefore, should not expect that their Personal Information would be completely removed from myhosting.com’s systems in response to an accepted request for deletion. 

If your Personal Information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct update, or delete it by making the change on our member information page or by emailing our Customer Support at [support@myhosting.com](mailto:support@myhosting.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

myhosting.com reserves the right to decline access to Personal Information where disclosure of the information requested is not required, as per Division 1, Clause 9 of PIPEDA.

Where information will not or cannot be disclosed, the individual making the request will be provided with the reasons for non-disclosure, pursuant to the principal in Schedule 1, Clause 4.9.4 of PIPEDA. Where information will be disclosed, myhosting.com will endeavor to provide the information in question within a reasonable time and no later than thirty (30) days following the request. 

myhosting.com will not respond to repetitious or vexatious requests for access. In determining whether a request is repetitious or vexatious, myhosting.com will consider such factors as the frequency with which information is updated, the purpose for which the information is used, and the nature of the information.

To guard against fraudulent requests for access, myhosting.com will require sufficient information to allow it to confirm the identity of the person making the request before granting access or making corrections.

**Amendment of myhosting.com practices and this Policy**

This policy is in effect as of January 21, 2014. myhosting.com will from time to time review and revise its privacy practices and this Policy. In the event of any amendment, an appropriate notice will be posted on this Site, status blogs and/or online web forums. We may also notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. Policy changes will apply to the information collected from the date of posting of the revised Policy to myhosting.com’s website as well as to existing information held by myhosting.com.

**Questions**

If you have any questions about the privacy practices of myhosting.com, or you wish to access your Personal Information, please contact:

**Legal and Compliance - SoftCom Inc.**  
1610 - 10 Bay Street  
Toronto, ON M5J 2R8

E-mail: [legal@softcom.com](mailto:legal@softcom.com)  
Fax:+1 866 357 8933
